# Kevin J Taylor kjtaylor19@gmail.com

214-437-6329

#### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS**

Possesses years of experience in Branch Office and OSJ inspections; Investment Adviser 206(4)-7; and Investment Company 38a-1 testing. Familiarity in Dodd-Frank (Swap Dealer & Volcker) regulation; Branch Operations; Operational Risk Management; Risk Assessments; Compliance Analysis, and Governance. Well-versed in FED, FINRA and SEC regulations and their application.

### **Core Competencies include:**

Analytical Thinking Project Management Influence & Persuasion
Continuous Education Regulatory Compliance Results Driven Leadership
Ethics Risk Management Strategic Planning
Management Audit Training/Development
Collaboration Talent Management Flexibility/Adaptability

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Commerzbank AG New York, New York

## Risk Assessments & Reviews - AVP

(2015-present)

- Evaluates internal controls through testing and gap analysis, to identify control weaknesses, deficiencies and provide solutions to complex issues.
- Formalizes testing results and presents findings to Senior Business and Compliance Management.
- Works with compliance, risk, and legal associates on remediation of findings and action plans.
- Coordinates the process of tracking and monitoring the Compliance-owned findings to ensure target dates are met with sufficient remediation to its action plans.
- Assists with the annual securities risk assessment process, and its evaluation of inherent risk, controls, and overall residual risk for its various groups within the Commerzbank branch and broker dealer.

### **Prudential Financial** Newark, New Jersey

(2012-2015)

## Manager - Compliance Testing Unit (CTU)

- Responsible for the coordination, and oversight of Broker Dealer, Investment Adviser 206(4)-7 and 38a-1 inspection reviews, focusing on regulatory requirements and effectiveness of its policies and procedures.
- Supervised, trained, and developed staff through the testing process, and overall professional development.
- Effectively collaborated with risk, compliance, legal and business management to ensure proper action plans are implemented for deficiencies noted during inspections.
- Managed regulatory developments.
- Developed and maintained the department's onboarding program for new associates.

#### Analyst - Compliance Testing Unit (CTU)

- Performed annual compliance inspections of Prudential's Broker Dealers.
- Conducted detailed internal reviews on compliance risk processes for various areas including brokerage mutual fund, private fund, variable contracts, group insurance, and other advisory services.
- Reviewed applicable policies and procedures; identified the overall risk associated with the potential of issues, failures and gaps within processes; assessed the adequacy of control systems, and presented the results to business unit management, risk management, as well as business unit compliance.
- Maintained Prudential's internal control standards, including timely implementation of internal audit points with any issues raised by external regulators.
- Drafted and amended Standard Operating Procedures

Kevin J Taylor Page 2

### National Regulatory Services San Diego, California (Virtual)

(2010-2012)

#### Auditor

- Traveled extensively, domestically and internationally, for various client sites performing regulatory audits for investment advisers and branch office audits for broker dealers.
- Evaluated the effectiveness of broker dealer representative's branch offices, and OSJs for adequate adherence to policies/procedures, and drafted reports of the findings and recommendations to the broker dealer.
- Reviewed advertising, drafted and amended firm procedures.
- Provided other filings and compliance services as needed.

### Wells Fargo & Company Dallas, Texas

(2003-2009)

### **Compliance Examiner**

- Implemented and monitored risk-based compliance programs to assure compliance with federal, state, agency, legal and regulatory requirements.
- Administered testing methodologies; evaluated the adequacy and effectiveness of policies, procedures, processes, initiatives, products and internal controls and identified issues resulting from internal and/or external compliance branch examinations. Drafted reports of findings and recommendations for compliance risk management.
- Collaborated with branch offices on the remediation of deficiencies found during the branch inspection, and provided education on rules and regulations.
- Managed staff associates and directed salary administration and rewards.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Major: Business Administration - Marketing Old Dominion University - Norfolk, Virginia

#### **LICENSES**

**Series 6** (Investment Company, Products/Variable Contracts Rep.)

**Series 63** (*Uniform Securities Agent State Law*)

CRD: 5375717

## **AFFILIATIONS**

National Society of Compliance Professionals (NSCP) Securities Industry and Financial Markets Association (SIFMA)